Kenan Bölükbaşı

Керан Андреев Давидов | Keran Andreev Davidov

Game Developer & Designer, CG Generalist, Architect

Ø	Kadıköy, İstanbul (Asia) - Turkey
2	+90 (542) 5362620
\bowtie	kenanb@6x13.com
\bowtie	kenanbolukbasi@gmail.com
ź	☑ kenanb.com ☑ 6x13.com
•	☑ blendernetwork.org/kenan-bolukbasi
₩	♥ kenanbolukbasi 🔊 blog.6x13.com
	• kenanb • 6x13

SUMMARY OF QUALIFICATIONS

Theoretical and applied knowledge in programming, design and media. Broad experience in project management. Experience in 3D (mesh, solid & CAD), 2D (raster, vector), and parametric graphics as well as asset pipelines and tools development. Blender 3D specialist (Blender Foundation Certified Trainer).

PERSONAL DETAILS

CITIZENSHIP Turkish, Bulgarian
DRIVER'S LICENCE B Class
DATE & PLACE OF BIRTH 28th January 1987, Bulgaria

EDUCATION

2005 - 2017	Architecture (B.Arch.) Istanbul Technical University, ITU School of Architecture, İstanbul
2001 - 2005	High School (Science and Math) Nilüfer Milli Piyango Anatolian High School, Bursa

CONFERENCES & WORKSHOPS

TALKS GIVEN

2016	Toxicity in Gaming: Negative Effects of Prioritizing Player Motivation in World Design ITU School of Architecture, Taşkışla, İstanbul
2014	Prototyping & Optimizing Game Asset Workflow Blender Conference, Amsterdam
2014	Automated Sprite Rendering System in Blender Libre Graphics Meeting, Leipzig
2014	Blender Python Programming Workshop BlendFX Studios, Leipzig
2011	AudioSpaces LiveCoding Workshop ITU School of Architecture, Taşkışla, İstanbul

PARTICIPATION

2015	Game Developers Conference EU 2015 (Cologne) UBM Tech
2014	Blender Conference (Amsterdam) Blender Foundation
2014	Libre Graphics Meeting (Leipzig) <i>LGM Crew</i>
2014	Blender Python Workshop (Leipzig) Kenan Bölükbaşı
2011	IAF Compositing Workshop (İstanbul) Özgür Gülbir

WORK EXPERIENCE

6x13 Games, İstanbul

JAN 2015 - [CONT'D]

Founder, Project Leader & Developer

Project leader. Game design and development. Graphics design and game asset creation. Prototyping, pipeline optimization.

- Design, development and artwork of WreckJumper[WIP], forced-perspective sci-fi TBS with dynamic puzzle elements.
- Game design, development, project management, graphics and user interface design of Twiniwt, the globally featured symmetrical movement puzzle.
- Project management & development of 1FPS Game Series.
- Cocos2d-x based in-house cross-platform game framework.
- Data structure design and development of the visualization module for an architectural research project at ITU. It aims to develop facades using evolutionary algorithms.
- Development of Fossicker, open source asset prospector.
- Invited industry participant at some Architectural Design Computing Master's Program classes at ITU.

EKSERIYA STUDIOS, İSTANBUL AUG 2013 – JAN 2015 Graphics Department Lead & TD

Decision making on graphics technology and workflow. Workflow optimization software development. Game asset creation, shading and lighting. Pipeline integration and prototyping.

- Asset pipeline automation system (import, lighting, rendering, compositing & atlas) for mobile RTS, Silicon Wars.
- Environment art and map editor for Riot Defense game.
- Pseudo 3D graphics R&D for Football Wizard game assets.

FREELANCE, İSTANBUL

Jun 2011 - Feb 2014

Visualization Artist

Archviz for various firms. Modeling & rendering of office furniture catalog of Bürosit as well as indoor visualizations.

EFOR EVENTS & SIMMETRICO, BAKU AUG 2011 – SEP 2011 Assistant Site Manager

Construction site management of a large steel structure for the wedding event of Azerbaijani President İlham Aliyev's daughter, in a multinational (Italian, Turkish & Azerbaijani) environment.

SosyalMedya.CO, İstanbul

FEB 2011 - MAR 2012

Author

Tech industry reports. Column in monthly e-journal. Interview with former Turkey & MEA Marketing Manager of Google.

EFOR EVENTS, İSTANBUL

JUL 2010 - APR 2013

Event Supervisor

Workflow & stage manager. Major events: Windows 8 Turkey Launch, Kenan Doğulu concert, VIP trip to Czech Republic. Clients: Microsoft, TeliaSonera, Huawei, Volvo, Doğuş, Soyak.

AŞÇIOĞLU İNŞAAT, İSTANBUL

SEP 2009 - Nov 2009

Assistant Site Manager, Internship

Application supervision at Acıbadem Hospital building of Selenium Twins (BJK Süleyman Seba Complex) construction site.

ALPO Engineering, İstanbul

MAR 2007 - MAY 2007

3D Artist

Technical drawings, archviz, urban planning modeling.

PROJECTS & RECOGNITION

PROGRAMMING PROJECTS

Twiniwt Mobile Game, 6x13 Games 2017

An innovative symmetrical movement puzzle. Globally featured in the AppStore Puzzle and Board categories as well as the AppStore Turkey homepage. It works on all popular mobile and desktop platforms. Uses modified Cocos2d-x game engine, C and C++.

2016 1FPS Retro Game Series, 6x13 Games

3 games that work on all popular mobile and desktop platforms. Uses customized Cocos2d-x and C++.

2015 Fossicker, The Asset Prospector, 6x13 Games

An asset generator that regexp over asset name to create relevant dummies. Powerful plugin system relies on CLOS and Context Oriented Programming.

2014 Riot Game Map Editor, Ekseriya

Map editor, importer/exporter that lets users both define and tile assets on a grid, export & raytrace the scene. Uses Blender Game Engine and Python.

2013 Sprite Automation System, Ekseriya

A system for automated game asset creation workflow. Uses Python, Blender3D (BPY) and Bash.

Hy Programming Language Blender Integration 2013 Blender Python Module that adds HyLang support and lets users interactively script Blender using Hy.

2012

Common Lisp parser/reader and writer for IESNA LM-63 Photometry Standard files.

2011 **TwitGraph**

CL bubble diagram generator. Searchs & visualizes relationships among a #hashtag and its neighbours.

DESIGN PROJECTS

- 2016 ITU Architecture Program Senior Design Project Habitation for Syrian refugees, with a focus on integration and employment, in Süleymaniye, İstanbul.
- 2014 StumpWM Window Manager & HyLang Logos Winner of StumpWM Official Logo Design Contest. Official logo design of Hy Programming Language.
- 2010 Cankaya Ulvi Cemal Erkin Concert Hall & Cultural Center Architectural Design Competition Participation (with Gülsev Özbelen & Gizem Kaya)
- Nooka International Watch Design Competition 2010 Participation with Nooka Ploog-In Design
- 2009 **Akcansa Concrete Ideas Competition** Finalist (with Büşra Atabek)

COMMUNICATION SKILLS

ENGLISH

• Listening: C2 (Mastery)* Reading: C2 (Mastery)*

• Spoken Interaction: C2 (Mastery)* Spoken Production: C1 (Advanced)*

• Writing: C2 (Mastery)*

- Prep Class Nilüfer Milli Piyango Anatolian High School Technical English – ITU Academic Essay Writing – ITU Research Paper Writing - ITU
- Work experience in Baku in a multinational environment for a month. Ensuring communication among Italian, Turkish, Azerbaijani and other parties.

Work experience in Prague for two weeks.

Guidance to several VIP clients including top government officials and corporate executives.

Constant interaction with foreign English speakers via technical/social platforms and mail.

AZERBAIJANI

- Listening: B2 (Upper intermediate)* Reading: B1 (Intermediate)*
- A2 (Elementary)*
- A1 (Beginner)*
- · Work experience for a month in Baku. Several organizations with Azerbaijani clients.

TURKISH

- Native Speaker
- (*) Common European Framework of Reference for Languages

SOFTWARE SKILLS

GRAPHICS SOFTWARE

Blender 3D Inkscape

ImageMagick, FFMpeg

GIMP, Photoshop 3D Studio Max, Maya

BI & Cycles Renderers

Luxrender, Yafaray

AutoCAD, DraftSight

Luminance HDR

PROGRAMMING LANGUAGES

C / C++

Common Lisp, Scheme

Python, Factor

UNIX / Shell

Lua, HTML5

DEVELOPMENT TOOLS & LIBRARIES

Emacs

Visual Studio

GCC, Clang, MSBuild

GDB, LLDB, Valgrind

Make, CMake, Gradle

Git Version Control System Cocos2d-x Game Engine (C++)

Xcode, Android Studio

OPERATING SYSTEMS

GNU/Linux (Arch, Debian) ---Windows XP/7/8/10

macOS

DOCUMENTATION UTILITIES

T_EX / L^AT_EX Systems Org-Mode, Markdown Doxygen, Pandoc

MS Office, Libre Office, Scribus

Additional Information

Walking, Computer Science, Technology HOBBIES

Blogging, Literature, Charcoal Drawing

Free / Libre & Open Source Software, COMMUNITIES

Blender Network, Lisp Game Development,

Factor Language Development